{"topic":"HTML","questions":[{"id":1,"question":"Which of these is the HTML5 doctype?","a":"<!DOCTYPE html>","b":"<!DOCTYPE HTML PUBLIC \"-//W3C//DTD HTML 5//EN\" \"http://www.w3.org/TR/html5/strict.dtd\">","answer":"a"},{"id":2,"question":"What is the purpose of a doctype?","a":"It tells other developers which version of HTML the page uses","b":"It ensures that browsers render the page in standards mode","answer":"b"},{"id":3,"question":"What is the difference between standards mode and quirks mode in a browser?","a":"In standards mode, browsers follow the HTML and CSS specifications. In quirks mode, they emulate the nonstandard behaviour of legacy browsers","b":"In standards mode, browsers allow the execution of JavaScript on a page. In quirks mode, they do not","answer":"a"},{"id":4,"question":"What is the syntax for a HTML comment?","a":"/* Comment */","b":"<!-- Comment -->","answer":"b"},{"id":5,"question":"What are data- attributes used for?","a":"Embedding custom application data in HTML elements, enabling JavaScript to enhance the user experience without interacting with the server","b":"Describing the purpose of HTML elements to other developers, making future development of the page easier","answer":"a"},{"id":6,"question":"Which of these statements comparing localStorage and sessionStorage is correct?","a":"There is no difference between them, as they are both Web Storage mechanisms maintaining separate storage areas for individual domains","b":"Both maintain separate storage areas per domain, but while localStorage persists until explicitly deleted, sessionStorage only survives for the length of the browser session","answer":"b"},{"id":7,"question":"What is HTML5 application caching?","a":"Files specified by the cache manifest file are cached by the browser and made available to offline users","b":"Standard browser caching, but of pages implemented using HTML5 features","answer":"a"},{"id":8,"question":"Which of the below code blocks correctly enables HTML5 application caching?","a":"<html application-cache=\"enabled\">...</html>","b":"<html manifest=\"myCacheManifest.appCache\">...</html>","answer":"b"},{"id":9,"question":"Which of these statements correctly compares the 'async' and 'defer' attributes of <script> tags?","a":"Both will download script files during HTML parsing. Defer scripts will execute in the order they are referenced once parsing has completed, whereas async scripts will pause parsing to execute when ready","b":"Async scripts download during HTML parsing and execute when ready, whereas defer scripts are only downloaded and executed at the end of HTML parsing","answer":"a"},{"id":10,"question":"Which of the following would correctly specify that the content of a page was written in English?","a":"<meta content=\"lang=en\" />","b":"<html lang=\"en\">","answer":"b"},{"id":11,"question":"On a page containing content in multiple languages, how would you indicate which languages were used for which areas of content?","a":"Specify the primary language on the <html> element, and then any other languages used on the elements that contain them, e.g. '<html lang=\"en\">' later followed by '<section lang=\"fr\">'","b":"Specify all languages included in the page on the <html> element, e.g. '<html lang=\"en,fr\">'","answer":"a"},{"id":12,"question":"What is semantic markup?","a":"Markup which describes the structure of its content for the purpose of being rendered by the browser","b":"Markup which reinforces the meaning of its content, and therefore describes that meaning to both browsers and developers","answer":"b"},{"id":13,"question":"What is a HTML5 web worker?","a":"JavaScript running as a background task, independent from other currently executing JavaScript, without affecting page performance","b":"The process which runs the JavaScript of your page in its standard single-threaded environment","answer":"a"},{"id":14,"question":"Which of these statements correctly compares cookies and localStorage?","a":"A cookie has a storage limit of 4KB whereas localStorage has a limit of 5MB (per domain). The contents of both gets sent with each server request","b":"A cookie has a storage limit of 4KB and gets sent with every server request, whereas localStorage has a limit of 5MB (per domain) and is only read client-side","answer":"b"},{"id":15,"question":"Which of these statements is true about tags being added/removed in HTML5?","a":"Tags such as <article>, <canvas> and <video> were added in HTML5, and tags such as <center>, <frameset> and <applet> were removed","b":"Tags such as <article>, <canvas> and <video> were added in HTML5, and no tags were removed","answer":"a"},{"id":16,"question":"When should you use a <section> element?","a":"To define a particular area of a page as it will be laid out when rendered in a browser","b":"To define a thematic grouping of content in a document","answer":"b"},{"id":17,"question":"When should you use an <article> element?","a":"To define a self-contained block of content which could be independently reused elsewhere","b":"To define a group of related content blocks, which would not make sense if reused outside of the current context","answer":"a"},{"id":18,"question":"When should you use a <header> element, and how many of these does it make sense to have in a single page?","a":"The <header> element is intended to be used for specifying the header for a whole document. It therefore only makes sense to have one <header> per page","b":"The <header> element can be used for specifying the header for an entire document, or just for part of it (e.g. an <article>). It can therefore make sense to have multiple headers on a page","answer":"b"},{"id":19,"question":"When should you use an <aside> element?","a":"To define content related to the content block it is placed in, but which should be considered separate from that related content (like a sidebar)","b":"To promote an unrelated content block within the current content block (like an advert)","answer":"a"},{"id":20,"question":"When is it appropriate to use the <nav> element?","a":"For any set of navigation links","b":"For major groups of navigation links only","answer":"b"},{"id":21,"question":"What is the WAI-ARIA specification and what is its purpose?","a":"It is the Web Accessibility Initiative - Accessible Rich Internet Applications Suite. It provides ways of making web content/applications more accessible to users with disabilities","b":"It is the Web Accessibility Initiative - Accessible Rich Internet Applications Suite. It provides ways of making developing web content/applications more accessible to students looking to get started with web development","answer":"a"},{"id":22,"question":"What kind of things would you do when implementing a web application to adopt the principles of the WAI-ARIA standard?","a":"Use semantic markup, along with HTML comments and descriptive attributes, to support new developers in understanding the implementation of your application","b":"Use native HTML5 elements, along with attributes representing roles, states and properties, to provide additional information to assistive browser technologies","answer":"b"},{"id":23,"question":"How do you specify the charset of a HTML5 document, as opposed to a HTML4 document?","a":"HTML4 required the use of '<meta http-equiv=\"Content-Type\" content=\"text/html; charset=UTF-8\">', whereas HTML5 supports '<meta charset=\"UTF-8\">'","b":"In both cases, use '<meta http-equiv=\"Content-Type\" content=\"text/html; charset=UTF-8\">'","answer":"a"},{"id":24,"question":"With the HTML5 drag and drop feature, how would you make an element draggable?","a":"Using the attribute 'drag=\"enabled\"'","b":"Using the attribute 'draggable=\"true\"'","answer":"b"},{"id":25,"question":"When using the HTML5 drag and drop feature, how would you manage the data to transfer?","a":"Using the dataTransfer property of the drag event, and its setData() and getData() functions","b":"By manually controlling a custom property on the drag event","answer":"a"},{"id":26,"question":"What does the postMessage() function introduced in HTML5 web messaging make possible?","a":"The sending of messages between various DOM elements on the same page","b":"The sending of messages between windows across domains","answer":"b"}]}